<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.4+"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>647618</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-03 17:25:00 -0700</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Convert Find Bar (in-page search) to a Doorhanger notification</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-07 11:33:48 -0700</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Client Software</classification>
          <product>Firefox</product>
          <component>Toolbars</component>
          <version>Trunk</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>UNCONFIRMED</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>--</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          
          <reporter name="Paul [sabret00the]">sabret00the</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Nobody; OK to take it and work on it">nobody</assigned_to>
          <cc>dugar.siddhartha</cc>
    
    <cc>xtc4uall</cc>
          <qa_contact>toolbars</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_blocking_fx>---</cf_blocking_fx>
          <cf_blocking_20>---</cf_blocking_20>
          <cf_status_20>---</cf_status_20>
          <cf_blocking_192>---</cf_blocking_192>
          <cf_status_192>---</cf_status_192>
          <cf_blocking_191>---</cf_blocking_191>
          <cf_status_191>---</cf_status_191>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5389599</commentid>
            <who name="Paul [sabret00the]">sabret00the</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-03 17:25:24 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:2.2a1pre) Gecko/20110403 Firefox/4.2a1pre
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:2.2a1pre) Gecko/20110403 Firefox/4.2a1pre

Currently the find bar is at the bottom of the screen. Though there are plans to improve usability by having them become tab modal. We should further continue by putting the search in a more prominent position i.e. as a door hanger where we are able to present the field in a more user-centric manner.

Reproducible: Always</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5390352</commentid>
            <who name="sdrocking">dugar.siddhartha</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-04 11:29:59 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Something like what google chrome does would look better IMO</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5394617</commentid>
            <who name="Paul [sabret00the]">sabret00the</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 09:56:55 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; cc: dugar.siddhartha@gmail.comSomething like what google chrome does would look better IMO

Well it&apos;s a very similar concept, but the manner in which we present things should be uniform. Suddenly growing the navbar for this fits with nothing else. Where are dropping a doorhanger from the awesome bar is in line with what we do for other things.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5394725</commentid>
            <who name="sdrocking">dugar.siddhartha</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 11:04:27 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>1. At present the find bar is a toolbar and a doorhanger would be nowhere close to that. This would again raise issues as we had in case of the status bar removal.
2. Doorhangers also cover content area considerably and this has already been an issue with the url popups. Also persistent doorhangers would appear bad after page navigation.
A new overlaying toolbar within the content area has no such issues and would be pretty enough. Also there are addons and styles using the current layout, they should not completely break with this change.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5394784</commentid>
            <who name="Paul [sabret00the]">sabret00the</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 11:33:48 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; 1. At present the find bar is a toolbar and a doorhanger would be nowhere close
&gt; to that. This would again raise issues as we had in case of the status bar
&gt; removal.
Nowhere close to that how? By definition the find bar acts in the same manner as a doorhanger anyway. If you as a user want it to persist, you can make it do so.

&gt; 2. Doorhangers also cover content area considerably and this has already been
&gt; an issue with the url popups. Also persistent doorhangers would appear bad
&gt; after page navigation.
There are already bugs being worked on to keep find content at the centre at the page. There are also bugs being worked on to make in-page find tab-modal.

&gt; A new overlaying toolbar within the content area has no such issues and would
&gt; be pretty enough. Also there are addons and styles using the current layout,
&gt; they should not completely break with this change.
It&apos;s up to addon authors and them authors to maintain their creations, not up to Mozilla to delay changes or avoid changes because authors are put out.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>