<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.4+"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>647714</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-04 11:05:00 -0700</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>browser.tabs.autohide hides menu button as well when only one tab</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-04 11:05:41 -0700</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Client Software</classification>
          <product>Firefox</product>
          <component>Tabbed Browser</component>
          <version>Trunk</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>--</priority>
          <bug_severity>critical</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Josh Triplett">josh</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Nobody; OK to take it and work on it">nobody</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact>tabbed.browser</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_blocking_fx>---</cf_blocking_fx>
          <cf_blocking_20>---</cf_blocking_20>
          <cf_status_20>---</cf_status_20>
          <cf_blocking_192>---</cf_blocking_192>
          <cf_status_192>---</cf_status_192>
          <cf_blocking_191>---</cf_blocking_191>
          <cf_status_191>---</cf_status_191>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5390326</commentid>
            <who name="Josh Triplett">josh</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-04 11:05:41 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Filing this bug with a high severity, because it can get a user into a state they can&apos;t easily recover from, even by restarting the browser.

The preference browser.tabs.autohide (exposed in the UI as Preferences-&gt;Tabs-&gt;&quot;Always show the tab bar&quot;) determines whether the tab bar appears with only one tab visible.  With this preference set to true, the tab bar only appears when the user has two or more tabs open.

If the user has the menu bar disabled, such that the menu button appears on the tab bar, then when the tab bar disappears, the menu button disappears with it.  That also removes access to Preferences, so if the user toggled the preference that way, they can&apos;t get back to the preferences dialog to undo it.  Thus, the user either has to go to about:config and manually fix the underlying preference, or open a new tab (via keyboard, middle-click, or the context menu) to make the tab bar appear.  If the user doesn&apos;t know how to do either of those things already, they can&apos;t recover.

This also hides any other controls on the tab bar, which may prove sub-optimal now that toolbar customization works with the tab bar.

(Also notable: if you hide other toolbars via customization, then this situation results in no toolbars whatsoever, and thus no ability to access the customize dialog either.)

I originally encountered this issue when experimenting with Firefox to try to configure it to use only windows rather than tabs, for use with a tabbed window manager.  Unfortunately, customization does not allow moving the menu button to the navigation bar (or anywhere else); see bug 180164 for that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>