<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.4+"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>647975</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-06 04:45:00 -0700</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Google calculator search suggestions no longer appear [caused by HTTPS Everywhere]</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-07 09:28:40 -0700</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Client Software</classification>
          <product>Firefox</product>
          <component>Extension Compatibility</component>
          <version>4.0 Branch</version>
          <rep_platform>x86</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows 7</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>--</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <votes>1</votes>
          
          <reporter name="WBT">firstpeterfourten</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Nobody; OK to take it and work on it">nobody</assigned_to>
          <cc>alex_mayorga</cc>
    
    <cc>bugcuddler</cc>
    
    <cc>hskupin</cc>
          <qa_contact>extension.compatibility</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_blocking_fx>---</cf_blocking_fx>
          <cf_blocking_20>---</cf_blocking_20>
          <cf_status_20>---</cf_status_20>
          <cf_blocking_192>---</cf_blocking_192>
          <cf_status_192>---</cf_status_192>
          <cf_blocking_191>---</cf_blocking_191>
          <cf_status_191>---</cf_status_191>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392138</commentid>
            <who name="WBT">firstpeterfourten</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 04:45:31 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0

Google Calculator search suggestions - or perhaps any search suggestion list of length 1 - no longer appears in Firefox 4.

I&apos;m used to using the Google search bar as a handy in-browser calculator that doesn&apos;t take up any extra space (as an add-on would) and can handle complex expressions.  In FF3, all I have to do is type in the expression, maybe with an equals sign (=) at the end, and it shows me the calculation result as a single search suggestion.  I can then remember the result and input it wherever needed.

Reproducible: Always

Steps to Reproduce:
In Google Search bar, type in a mathematical expression followed by an equals sign, such as &quot;2*2=&quot;.
Actual Results:  
Nothing happens. No search suggestions are shown.
(If you hit enter to conduct the search, the result is displayed, but it takes over the tab to display the result).

Expected Results:  
A single search suggestion appears, namely &quot;=      4&quot;.
This is the useful behavior of FF3.

Personally, I see this as a major feature that broke in the &quot;upgrade.&quot;  I will not install FF4 on my other machines, and may revert on this one for my general use, until the bug is fixed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392297</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Ahlblom">bugcuddler</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 08:18:43 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>It works for me with a clean profile and:
Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.0; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0

I do get the answer as a the topmost suggestion below the search bar and I do not need to press enter.

Maybe you should test again with a new profile:
https://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Basic%20Troubleshooting#w_8-make-a-new-profile</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392757</commentid>
            <who name="Henrik Skupin [:whimboo]">hskupin</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 11:34:17 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Are you talking about the Google Toolbar search field or the Firefox own one? As far as I can see it&apos;s for the Toolbar one, which you will have to report to the Google team instead.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392833</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Ahlblom">bugcuddler</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 11:52:10 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>To clarify, the thing I tested successfully in Comment 1 was the Firefox native search field in the Navigation toolbar.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392970</commentid>
            <who name="alex_mayorga">alex_mayorga</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 12:45:19 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Typing &quot;4-6=&quot; (no quotes) on the Minefield search bar gives me the result of &quot;=-2&quot; as the first Suggestion on Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.0; rv:2.2a1pre) Gecko/20110406 Firefox/4.2a1pre ID:20110406030427</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392998</commentid>
            <who name="Henrik Skupin [:whimboo]">hskupin</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 12:57:53 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sounds like an installed extension causes this problem for you in the original profile. Please disable extensions step by step or try safe mode: http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Safe+Mode</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5393801</commentid>
            <who name="WBT">firstpeterfourten</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 18:48:02 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; Are you talking about the Google Toolbar search field or the Firefox own one?
&gt; As far as I can see it&apos;s for the Toolbar one, which you will have to report to
&gt; the Google team instead.
Firefox&apos;s search field, not Google&apos;s Toolbar.

(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; Sounds like an installed extension causes this problem for you in the original
&gt; profile. Please disable extensions step by step or try safe mode:
&gt; http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Safe+Mode

Thanks Henrik.  I should have thought of that but didn&apos;t, because I thought I had all the add-ons (and more) in my FF3 install that I had in FF4.

The culprit was (is) HTTPS Everywhere, by the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF), at https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere.  Unchecking the Google Search translator cleared this issue up.

I have also checked and duplicated the issue on FF 3.16.13.  Perhaps I installed this extension at about the same time as the upgrade!

I&apos;m reporting the issue to their mailing list, with a link to this bug report.  I&apos;ve set the status here to resolved. 

Thanks Thomas, Henrik, and Alex for your help!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5394005</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Ahlblom">bugcuddler</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 23:15:19 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>WBT, just some extra information that may be relevant to you:

You may consider replacing your Google search engine with one of the Google SSL search engines, like:
https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/google-ssl-search/

You can select Manage Search Engines by left clicking to the left in the search field.

There are even more SSL search engines on https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/search-tools/ so you can search with SSL on YouTube, Wikipedia etc as well.


And if you put something like https://encrypted.google.com/search?q= in keyword.URL in about:config the searches done via the location bar will be encrypted as well.
http://kb.mozillazine.org/Keyword.URL</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5394540</commentid>
            <who name="Henrik Skupin [:whimboo]">hskupin</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 09:28:40 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>WBT, thanks for your feedback. It would be great if you can get in touch with the add-on developers and tell them about this issue.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>