<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.4+"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>648042</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-06 11:09:00 -0700</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>url autocomplete stops working over time</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-11 14:14:10 -0700</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Client Software</classification>
          <product>Firefox</product>
          <component>Location Bar</component>
          <version>4.0 Branch</version>
          <rep_platform>x86</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Mac OS X</op_sys>
          <bug_status>UNCONFIRMED</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>--</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          
          <reporter name="Marty Sachs">msachs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Nobody; OK to take it and work on it">nobody</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact>location.bar</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_blocking_fx>---</cf_blocking_fx>
          <cf_blocking_20>---</cf_blocking_20>
          <cf_status_20>---</cf_status_20>
          <cf_blocking_192>---</cf_blocking_192>
          <cf_status_192>---</cf_status_192>
          <cf_blocking_191>---</cf_blocking_191>
          <cf_status_191>---</cf_status_191>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5392656</commentid>
            <who name="Marty Sachs">msachs</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-06 11:09:43 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10.6; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10.6; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0

In previous versions of Firefox, url autocomplete worked flawlessly.  Since updating to Firefox 4, while url autocomplete works initially upon starting Firefox, after its been running for a while (time varies) the url autocomplete functions stops working.  Instead an endless loop of what appears to be searching takes place (spinning wheel to the left of the url bar).

Reproducible: Always

Steps to Reproduce:
1.start Firefox 4
2. enter the first few letters of a url in the location bar field; this should auto complete
3. try this again after Firefox has been running for a while, and the instead of auto completing the url, one sees a spinning wheel to the left of the url bar.
Actual Results:  
After time, instead of auto completing a url, one sees a spinning wheel to the left of the url bar.

Expected Results:  
As long as Firefox is open, the url auto complete function should continue to work.

I have tried restarting with all add-ons disabled and experience the same issue. So, it doesn&apos;t appear to be due to an incompatibility with an add-on.  

However, my user directory is on a remote AFP server and in the past, this has presented issues for Firefox.  However, I have never experienced this particular issue with versions prior to Firefox 4.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5401576</commentid>
            <who name="Marty Sachs">msachs</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-11 14:14:10 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>This may be related to the memory issue described by others (see bug 645310 and bug 646773).  When I&apos;m experiencing the auto-complete problem, I am also seeing that Firefox 4 is using an enormous amount of memory.  When I try to quit, the process is still running and need to do a forced quit.  This may also be related to bug 646615, which I also experience at the same time I&apos;m experiencing this issue.  When Firefox 4 is doing that auto-complete properly and link colors (especially in Google searches) are appearing properly, memory use seems much lower.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>