<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.4+"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>648437</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-07 18:04:00 -0700</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Lightning Snooze Drop down disappears off screen-right if reminder is screen-right</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-11 12:04:21 -0700</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Client Software</classification>
          <product>Calendar</product>
          <component>Alarms</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>x86</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows 7</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>--</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="john ruskin">educmale</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Nobody; OK to take it and work on it">nobody</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact>alarms</qa_contact>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5395589</commentid>
            <who name="john ruskin">educmale</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 18:04:28 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2.16) Gecko/20110319 Firefox/3.6.16
Build Identifier: 1.0b2 Lightning; Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2.15) Gecko/20110303 Lightning/1.0b2 Thunderbird/3.1.9

A small, but correctable error....

I had a reminder pop up, and it was placed on my screen towards the right edge.   On selecting snooze, then modifying the time, I was unable to see the cancel/check buttons.

Right now, the the drop down box aligns-left with the snooze field.

Instead, the drop down box should 
1) slide towards the right if the reminder box is too far to the right to allow one to see the full drop.

Alternatively: 
2) Place the check/cancel buttons below the time/unit fields, instead of to the right; or,
3) Left Align the snooze field and the drop down list

Personally, I prefer 1) over 2), and 2) over 3)

Similarly, the all-event snooze disappears screen-right, and screen-bottom.  And in the event one moves the reminder screen low, the one-event may also disappear screen bottom.   I recommend that each of the drop down lists check for placement on the existing screen, rather than fold out and beyond any edges

Reproducible: Always

Steps to Reproduce:
1.  Innocently place reminder window towards the right side of the screen
2.  Wait for an inevitable reminder, later, and
3.  Attempt a snooze setting for specific events
4.  Forget that the check/cancel buttons are now hidden



Evaluate the placement of the drop down lists for the one-event and the all-event snooze buttons, and force the list to move onto the screen if it would fall off the edge.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5399663</commentid>
            <who name="john ruskin">educmale</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-10 16:36:23 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>My error:  remove alt suggestion 3, above, as I meant right-align, and on realizing that, realized that the reminder could be screen-right, making that solution incorrect, anyway.

On thinking: only #1, checking for screen edge alignment would be sensible, to eliminate any error, regardless of where the reminder box is parked...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5401146</commentid>
            <who name="Philipp Kewisch [:Fallen]">philipp</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-11 12:04:21 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Possibly all we need to do here is to make the calendar-snooze-popup binding extend chrome://global/content/bindings/popup.xml#popup-base. This should happen automatically, but we&apos;re doing a bit of hackery to make the textbox work.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>