<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="3.6.4+"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>648520</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-08 06:30:00 -0700</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>history missing after restart</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-08 12:35:47 -0700</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Client Software</classification>
          <product>Firefox</product>
          <component>Bookmarks &amp; History</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>x86_64</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows 7</op_sys>
          <bug_status>UNCONFIRMED</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>--</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          
          <reporter>victor50</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Nobody; OK to take it and work on it">nobody</assigned_to>
          <cc>mak77</cc>
          <qa_contact>bookmarks</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_blocking_fx>---</cf_blocking_fx>
          <cf_blocking_20>---</cf_blocking_20>
          <cf_status_20>---</cf_status_20>
          <cf_blocking_192>---</cf_blocking_192>
          <cf_status_192>---</cf_status_192>
          <cf_blocking_191>---</cf_blocking_191>
          <cf_status_191>---</cf_status_191>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5396336</commentid>
            <who name="">victor50</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-08 06:30:13 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64; rv:2.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/4.0

After restarting (for instance updating an add-on) or when killing FF, large chunks of history are missing, about 1 day of history before the restart. Putting the machine in sleep-mode might be affecting this. Sometimes also recently added bookmarks from the same period disappear.

Reproducible: Sometimes</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5396675</commentid>
            <who name="Marco Bonardo [:mak]">mak77</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-08 09:57:03 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>why would you be killing firefox? that can arguably cause a small dataloss, but just the last few minutes, not a full day. If you shutdown the browser usually do you notice the problem?
Btw, this sounds strange, do you have add-ons interacting with history or bookmarks?
Where do you miss history, you don&apos;t see it in the menu, or in the sidebar/Library?
Could you check if you have .corrupt files in your profile folder?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5397148</commentid>
            <who name="">victor50</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-08 11:59:30 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>Killing is still sometimes necessary when FF complains it is already running and won&apos;t (re)start. I hardly ever shut down the browser as I put my PC on standby most of the time.
I miss history in the sidebar as well as in the &quot;view all history&quot; I don&apos;t use the history menu.
If you mean *.corrupt files: I didn&apos;t find any. 

The first time I noticed this was after I tried to install Quickrestart addon. following the post on https://addons.mozilla.org/nl/firefox/addon/quickrestart/ (I think this was on the same day I installed FF4): 

If you guys wanted it for v4.0 to the following -&gt; download xpi file (with different browser), then OPEN it (don&apos;t extract, just open) with archive extracting software (WinRAR, WinZip, IZArc). There&apos;s a file called install.rdf, double click to open it, find line &quot;&lt;em:maxVersion&gt;&quot; and change value from 3.6.* to 4.*.*. Then close the xpi archive file, it will ask for update the archive with updated install.rdf -&gt; click yes

N2GetherNow op April 1, 2011

 afterwards I wrote: 

Wouldn&apos;t recommend for FF4

If you try the trick described below: I got serious trouble resulting in the menu bar being visible but not usable and finally all my toolbars were blank. On top of that some history was missing and a recent addition to my bookmarks. The restart option is not visible in the mini-menu you get when you turn off the menu-bar so you will have to use the keyboard or add the button. Better wait for a true and tested version wich I hope will come soon.

Victor Onrust op April 2, 2011

After that I disabled it but did not remove it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5397200</commentid>
            <who name="Marco Bonardo [:mak]">mak77</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-08 12:29:29 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>forcing compatibility on an add-on can cause a lot of troubles, it&apos;s possible it has somehow corrupted your profile, creating a new profile and exporting old data to it could be the best choice.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5397215</commentid>
            <who name="">victor50</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-08 12:35:47 -0700</bug_when>
            <thetext>I will try and let you know in a few weeks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>